minecraftpocket-servers.com 2019-11-28

# Privacy Policy

We collect only the following data for the use of " **MinecraftPocket-Servers.com** ". We never sell your personal information to third parties. If you have any questions or concerns regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at: [admin@minecraftpocket-servers.com](mailto:admin@minecraftpocket-servers.com)

**Last Revision: August 20th, 2019**

## __What Data Do We collect?

* * *

#### __Access Information

Like many other websites, we make use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, type of browser, type of operating system, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date/time, referring/exit pages....

 _IP addresses and other such information are not linked to any other information that are personally identifiable_

.

#### __User Account

When you register on " **MinecraftPocket-Servers.com** ", you must provide a nickname and a valid email address. We only use these information for notices, warnings, internal newsletters, password retrieval and account activation.

On registration and each login action, we also collect the IP address used. We only collect this information for two purposes: 

  * Abuse detection and prevention
  * Security measure for account protection

When using our Premium option, you must provide before payment the following information : Name and firstname, Company Name (if applicable), Country of residence and a VAT number (if applicable). These information will be used for our invoices and tax purpose. These information can be transmitted to financial authorities for tax and accountant purpose.

#### __Vote Information

When you vote for a server on " **MinecraftPocket-Servers.com** ", we collect the following information : IP address, Country associated with the IP address , Referrer URL, User agent (browser and system used), SteamID (if provided).

The IP address can be shared with a third party for abuse detection (usage of VPN/Proxy). See "Third Parties" section for more information.

#### __Server Information

When you register a server on " **MinecraftPocket-Servers.com** ", we collect all information you provide us with. By registering your server, you accept that we publicly publish some information, like your server's IP address, server port...

## __Data Retention Time

* * *

#### __Access Information

Access information stored in our log files can be kept up to two years for security needs.

#### __User Account

Data associated with user account are kept until user request removal of his data. A copy of these data are stored in external backups and can be kept up to 20 days after the removal request.

#### __Vote Information

Vote data (See "What Data Do We collect?") stored in our database are kept for one month.

#### __Server Information

Server information are kept until user request removal. A copy of these data are stored in external backups and can be kept up to 20 days after the removal request.

## __Data Removal

* * *

#### __Access Information

Access information are removed automatically based on our log rotation settings. See "Data Retention Time" for more information.

#### __User Account

Each user has an option to delete immediatly his account and data associated with it in our database. Copies of these data stored in our backups are automatically deleted after the retention time indicated in "Data Retention Time".

#### __Vote Information

Vote information are removed automatically. See "Data Retention Time" for more information.

#### __Server Information

Each user has an option to delete immediatly the data associated with his server. Copies of these data stored in our backups are automatically deleted after the retention time indicated in "Data Retention Time".

## __Cookies

* * *

#### __What Are Cookies?

A cookie is a small text file that a website saves on your computer or mobile device when you visit the site. It enables the website to remember your actions and preferences (such as login, language, font size and other display preferences) over a period of time, so you don't have to keep re-entering them whenever you come back to the site or browse from one page to another.

#### __How Do We Use Cookies?

We use cookies to store your session information. This allow us to logged you in automatically. You can remove and disable cookies by modifying the settings in your browser. However, keep in mind that this may cause you to be unable to login on " **MinecraftPocket-Servers.com** ". 

We use cookies with our vote system to help us detect abuse. You can remove and disable cookies by modifying the settings in your browser. However, keep in mind that this may cause you to be unable to vote on " **MinecraftPocket-Servers.com** ". 

## __Third Parties and Third Party Cookies

* * *

Our website uses various third party services. Some of these third party service might use cookies to work.   
**European citizens might disable them using our privacy setting banner.**

By disabling third party services, you will not be able to use some parts of our website.

#### __Google Analytics

Our website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"). We don't use any "Advertising Features" and "IP Anonymization" feature is enabled. This service requires use of cookies.

#### __Google Adsense

Our website uses Google AdSense, a web advertising service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"). This service requires use of cookies.

#### __Google reCAPTCHA

Our website uses Google reCAPTCHA, a security service that protects your websites from spam and abuse provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"). This service requires use of cookies.

####  AddThis

Our website uses AddThis, a social bookmarking service provided by Oracle Corporation. This service requires use of cookies.

#### __IPHub

Our website uses IPHub, a Proxy/VPN detection service. When you use our vote feature, we transmit your IP address to IPHub. No other data are transmitted to IPHub.

#### __Cookie-Script

Our website uses Cookie-Script, a cookie management service to collect consent to third party cookies for European citizens. This service requires use of cookies that cannot be disabled.

#### __Cloudflare

Our website uses Cloudflare, a content delivery network and DDoS protection. This service requires use of cookies. More information [here](https://www.cloudflare.com/cookie-policy/).

## __Links To Other Websites

* * *

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide while visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

## __Other Terms

* * *

" **MinecraftPocket-Servers.com** " reserves the right to change the Privacy Policy at anytime with or without notice.
